Today, we're going to be talking about five tips for new entrepreneurs, but
we're going to be doing something a little bit different in today's video.
And what I mean by something different is we are actually going to be on a trail walk today doing this video
just because I feel like a lot of the times videos on entrepreneurship, business and finance in general are always super serious.
Instead of just like a conversation that people
would have with their younger selves per se.
And that's always the kind of content that I always look
for is just just like a conversation, just real shit, honestly.
So if you guys do enjoy this video, if you guys
enjoy this type of content, please leave us a like and subscribe.
I would really appreciate it. We have a ton of content coming
out on this channel and something I want to talk about real quick.
That's arguably more important than the tips I'll
be giving later today is figuring out your why.
And you don't if you don't understand what I mean by that, if you don't know what I'm saying, your
why is pretty much why you do what you're doing and why you're working so hard to achieve said goal.
Right. And the reason why figuring it out, figuring out your why is so
important is because some days are going to be better than others in entrepreneurship.
Some days you're going to wake up absolutely crushed today.
Everything that you seem to do just works out great.
Everything that you want to get
done gets done. Everything's good. Right.
But then you have the other side of the spectrum
where everything you're doing maybe isn't working out so well.
Maybe you get into a car accident before a big meeting
or maybe you fall into a ditch before your big meeting.
Who knows? Whatever it may be.
Whatever life throws your way, some days
are going to be better than others.
And you're going to have negative self-talk that comes in
occasionally and makes you question, why are you doing this?
Why are you working so hard
on this? You're not even seeing results.
You can't do this. You know, all
those negative self-talks and self-beliefs come in.
And your why is ultimately going to pull you through that and be able
to reassure you on why you're working so hard on what you're trying to achieve.
One more thing that's not talked about enough for
new entrepreneurs is that it is perfectly OK to work.
Work a job when you start your business.
And the reason being is
because you need money for rent.
You need money for food.
You need money to live. Right.
And a lot of businesses, when they first start, are not super profitable
or maybe are not enough for you to live off of solely from that.
So work a job. It's completely OK to
help fund your lifestyle and where you're currently at.
And then also put to inject
money into the business as well.
So that way it can grow and
allowing you to actually quit the job.
Let's go ahead and hop into these tips.
Besides this first tip.
The rest of the tips are no particular order.
But this first one is
like a golden rule of business.
You need to know sales.
Seriously, you need sales in order to
grow your business and to maintain your business.
Because if you cannot sell people into buying your
product or service, then you don't have a business.
You need to be able to find a way to consistently
get new customers in the door for your company to grow.
And one of the best quotes that I kind
of live by is if you're not growing, you're dying.
And it's true.
Because customer turnover, customer churn
is real and it will happen.
And you just need to be finding a new
way to constantly keep marketing yourself and selling your product.
So that way you can continue
to grow and stay in business.
My final point on sales is actually
a tip from my first mentor, Joe Soto.
And at the time I was
early on in my digital marketing company.
And what he told me was
to stop playing with my food.
And what he meant by that is I was
going into sales presentations and sales demos with potential clients.
Without actually practicing my sales pitch.
And he made the analogy of a professional athlete.
A professional athlete is
practicing and they're watching film.
I need to be doing the same as a salesperson.
I need to be role playing.
I need to be practicing my pitch.
I need to be watching film.
I need to be rewatching
these Zoom meetings that I have.
Pitching to people and listening to how I talk.
Listening to how I can handle certain scenarios better.
So train your sales like a professional athlete will.
And I guarantee you, you'll see results.
Tip number two.
Is to learn accounting.
And I'm really shouting at my younger self here.
Because I made so many poor
financial decisions as a new entrepreneur.
Because I didn't understand accounting.
Or really just understand how the
numbers worked in business at all.
So what I recommend for all new entrepreneurs.
Is to pick up a book.
Hire someone.
Or whatever.
By any means necessary that you
need to do to figure out accounting.
And at least have a basic knowledge yourself.
And this will allow you to
make just much better decisions in business.
And give you a much better
picture of where your business actually is.
Versus what you think it is.
I'm not going to lie guys.
This talking and shooting while
on a hike is pretty exhausting.
But it is pretty dope.
Let's carry on to tip number three.
Tip number three is what does
your customer onboarding process look like?
And what I'm really talking about here.
Is after someone has decided to
purchase from you or your business.
What does it look like after that?
And this is really useful.
And something you should think about.
For a couple reasons.
One is you want to eliminate buyers remorse.
And when people make decisions sometimes they regret it.
And you want to make
them feel comfortable with their decision.
And why they bought from you.
And the last thing you want to
have is a chargeback a day later.
Because they're like hey.
Don't actually want to move forward with it.
And you really just want to eliminate that.
The second thing is really especially
for people in service based businesses.
To set expectations correctly.
To eliminate problems in the future.
So you want to set expectations.
And the way to teach them what they can expect.
How your relationship is going to work.
How communication is handled.
And what are those next steps.
Implement this and think about
this early on in your business.
And you'll save yourself a
lot of headaches down the line.
Tip number four is investing in content and social media.
And the reason I say this is
because social media is so hot right now.
This is where the majority of people
are spending their time when they're at home.
Or on their phones.
Is they're looking at social media.
They're looking at different feeds.
And you can leverage this
for your business to grow it.
And especially utilizing your first three connections.
Such as your friends, family, and people you know.
If you just share the
right content that's meaningful and useful.
Giving people progress on the
updates you're making to your business.
And just things that you guys are doing.
It can reach out to
people and it will pay off.
You just have to be consistent.
One of the most creative ways
that I have seen social media used.
For someone to grow their business.
Is through my good friend Austin Smith.
Austin is a digital marketing owner.
And pretty much what he did.
Is he held up a stack of cash.
And pretty much said the message along the lines of.
Hey, if you'd like to get some of this cash.
All you have to do is
refer me to a friend or family.
Or business owner that you
think would benefit from my services.
And I will gladly pay you for that referral.
I wanted to jump on here.
And say thank you to those
who participated in my July giveaway.
I gave away $10,000.
The only thing you had to do is
put me in touch with a business owner.
And so what he did.
Is he closed I think probably close to $100,000.
Worth of business.
Because the video went viral in his local area.
And just think about what
that could do for your business.
Is if you just have one video go viral.
It can change your business.
And it can change your life forever.
Tip number five is to go out and network.
But I want you to network a
little bit differently than the other people.
A lot of people go out and network.
And just go out and hand out their business card.
And try to sell, sell,
sell their own products and services.
Without actually investing.
Into other people.
The best way to go out and network.
Is to actually go out
and invest in other people's stories.
Hear about their products.
Their service.
Hear about their story of
why they're doing what they're doing.
And if you're able to give people some free advice.
Some free value.
They are not only much more likely to remember you.
But they're also much more likely
to refer you down the line.
Even though they may not refer you immediately.
Or that same day.
Two months down the line.
They're much more likely to give you a call.
And say hey.
I have a great connection for you.
I think you guys should definitely meet up.
And that's the power of networking.
Is planting the seeds in other people.
So that way you can
grow your business passively over time.
Just through the power of relationships.
Some great books on how to build a better network.
Is how to win friends and influence people.
And then Giftology as well.
Is another great book for networking.
Hopefully you guys did enjoy today's video.
I know it's a little bit different
while doing it on the nature trail.
But I just wanted to switch it up.
So hopefully you guys did enjoy.
If you guys did.
Please leave us a like and subscribe.
We'd really appreciate it.
We'll catch you guys in the next one.